We want to catch the more specific exception first.
So I'm going to make a little function here.
And I'm going to call it division.
And it's going to take the number that to divide by.
So I'm going to just call that num.
And I'm going to say, try.
Result equals.
Let me make sure my indentation is correct here.
Result is going to equal to the value of pi divided by the user input number.
We're going to accept on arithmetic error.
And print out that we had a general math error.
Otherwise, I'm also going to accept on a special type of exception called the zero division error.
Why might this come up?
That means you're going to divide by zero and zero.
So if the number is zero, yeah.
I can say I divide by zero error.
I think you're going to have problems because the arithmetic is still wrong.
Oh, you missed the first item.
Oh, thank you.
When we just put that back in real quickly.
So result equals 3.14 divided by num.
And accept our arithmetic.
Got that right.
Yeah, error.
I'm going to print out math error.
And then I'm going to accept on zero division error.
And I'm going to print zero division.
Okay.
If I try to do division by zero, we're going to see something a little bit unexpected.
I'm going to get a math error.
And that's because the zero division error is the more specific error.
And arithmetic error is the more general one.
So by catching the more general exception first, I swallowed the more helpful error message.
And to figure out this exception hierarchy, you can look at the Python docs page.
And check it out.
There's a lot there.
The link is in the course website.
In general, it's pretty bad to catch exception in your code.
Because let's say I was using the GitHub API.
And I caught exception when I tried to use it.
I just completely lost context of what the general exception was.
And now I can't really change the flow of my program by what I can do with it.
The absolute worst thing that you can do is try some code, accept on exception.
And then do nothing.
Everything went fine, according to my code, right?
So this is called swallowing the exception.
You should at least try to log it or do something.
Maybe page your ops guy, depending on the severity of the error.
But by doing this, you'll really lose a lot of context.
And again, generally don't catch basic exception.
Or now generally, but definitely don't do that.
Whatever.
But it's even the worst form of this.